<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.2">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://snapfse.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://snapfse.com/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-08-31T18:28:24+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/feed.xml</id><title type="html">SNAP</title><subtitle>Special Needs Assistance Program for Social Engagement promotes socialization and friendship-making for neurodiverse communities.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">[Pitt News] SNAP collaborates with Pittsburgh Center for Arts and Media for neurodiversity mural</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/29/Pitt-news" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="[Pitt News] SNAP collaborates with Pittsburgh Center for Arts and Media for neurodiversity mural" /><published>2023-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/29/Pitt-news</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/29/Pitt-news"><![CDATA[<p><img src="https://pittnews.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/C_SNAPMural_JB-900x600.jpg" alt="Students participate in painting the SNAP mural on Sunday." /></p>

<p>By Anna Ligorio, Senior Staff Writer
JANUARY 29, 2023</p>

<p>Vivid swirls of red, orange, purple, yellow and blue paint filled two panels in Benedum Hall this Sunday, forming interlocked infinity symbols that hover over a rainbow background. Painted by members of the Special Needs Assistance Program for Social Engagement, these colors and designs will gradually come together over two weeks to create a mural celebrating neurodiversity. SNAP members split into groups to work on two separate panels that will form an 8-by-8-foot mural. The final product will hang on the first floor of Benedum Hall, and SNAP is planning an unveiling ceremony in late February to honor the work put into the mural.</p>

<p>SNAP is a student organization at Pitt with a mission to educate a …</p>

<p>Read the full article on the <a href="https://pittnews.com/article/178518/arts-and-entertainment/mural/">Pitt News</a></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Read the article fro Pitt News about us!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh SNAP! January Edition</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/16/newsletter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh SNAP! January Edition" /><published>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2023-01-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/16/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2023/01/16/newsletter"><![CDATA[<p>In this month’s newsletter, we will discuss the events hosted by the SNAP Club during the winter season. We will also provide updates on our progress in SNAP research, including the development of new surveys to support neurodiverse families and an AI-based app. Happy New Year!</p>

<p><strong>Upcoming Events</strong>:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Community Mural</li>
  <li>Fundraiser Run</li>
  <li>Chipotle Fundraiser</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="the-community-mural">The Community Mural</h2>
<p>We are excited to announce an upcoming event in Benedum Hall where we will be collaborating with the Pittsburgh Center for Arts and Media to create a neurodiversity mural. The mural will be directed by Artist Alison Zapata and will be on display in Benedum Hall, with the names of all contributors included. We are looking for a total of 16 participants, with 8 painting on Saturdays and 8 on Sundays, with an equal representation from SNAP Club and partnering organizations. The painting schedule is as follows:</p>

<ul>
  <li>January 21st: General Meeting for Everyone (10 am - 12 pm)</li>
  <li>January 28th and February 4th: Group A (10 am - 12 pm)</li>
  <li>January 29th and February 5th: Group B (10 am - 12 pm)</li>
  <li>Unveiling Ceremony (TBD, mid-late February)</li>
</ul>

<p>SNAP Club will provide all necessary materials, food, and accommodations. If you have any questions or are interested in participating, please contact Zachary Miller at zachamiller@pitt.edu or fill out the <a href="https://forms.gle/YQmEhVDyeQANkWtM7">sign-up form</a> (<a href="https://forms.gle/YQmEhVDyeQANkWtM7">https://forms.gle/YQmEhVDyeQANkWtM7</a>). We look forward to creating a masterpiece together!</p>

<h2 id="the-fundraiser-run">The Fundraiser Run</h2>
<p>We are excited to announce that we will be hosting a charity run in Schenley Park to raise funds for our community events and for charities that support neurodiverse families in need. The run will take place on Sunday, March 26th, 2023 and all proceeds will go towards these causes. More details will be shared soon.</p>

<h2 id="snap-volunteering-takes-off">SNAP Volunteering takes off</h2>

<p>SNAP Volunteering partners with UPMC’s Disability Resource Center (DRC) to provide accommodations for individuals with disabilities at UPMC Presbyterian and UPMC Shadyside hospitals. We collaborate with the DRC to meet patients’ physical, communicative, and emotional needs, with the goal of improving their hospital experience. We plan to expand to other hospitals in the future. Recently, we have started training volunteers and developing tools to assist patients. So far, we have helped over 100 patients and hope to assist many more. If you’re interested in volunteering, please fill out the form at <a href="https://forms.gle/uiNhPs8zqUA4Up2y5">https://forms.gle/uiNhPs8zqUA4Up2y5</a>. We hope to expand the program to other hospitals, including UPMC Children’s Hospital of Pittsburgh, UPMC Magee, and UPMC Mercy.</p>

<h2 id="developments-in-research">Developments in Research</h2>

<p>SNAP Research is conducting an Autism Family survey to gain a deeper understanding of the community’s needs and preferences for communication aid tools. The focus of the survey is to address the double empathy problem by developing a comprehensive communication system that incorporates all aspects of speech pragmatics. We are currently in the research and development phase, where we are carefully crafting the survey questions and format to ensure that we gather the most meaningful and relevant data. Our goal is to release the survey within the next year, so we can begin working on creating the communication tool. The survey will help us identify the key challenges that families with autism face when it comes to communication, and it will inform the design of the communication tool so that it addresses those challenges effectively. The survey will also gather information on the current communication aids that families are using, their effectiveness, and areas that need improvement. By gathering this information, we hope to create a communication tool that is tailored to help improve communication bidirectionally.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SNAP during the winter, research updates, and new surveys]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">ADHD Educational Talk</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/14/speaker-event" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ADHD Educational Talk" /><published>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/14/speaker-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/14/speaker-event"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong>: 11/14/2022<br />
<strong>Time</strong>: 5:00 PM - 6:00 PM<br />
<strong>Location</strong>: WPU 538 or Zoom (RSVP for Link)</p>

<p>Join SNAP for “<em>ADHD Educational Talk</em>” on Wednesday, November 14th at 5:00 pm in 538 William Pitt Union! The event will last one hour and include a moderated Q&amp;A. Tickets are not required for the event, but attendees must complete the RSVP form (E-mail us).</p>

<p>Participants with disabilities are encouraged to contact the SNAP Officers by E-mail at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">snapfse@gmail.com</code> for proper accommodations.</p>

<h2 id="about-kate-marhelko">About Kate Marhelko</h2>

<div class="w-25 float-start me-2 mb-2" style="max-width: 150px">
  <table>
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th style="text-align: center">![Maria Reading](/assets/marhelko.jpg){: .w-100 .img-thumbnail .d-block .img-fluid}</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">*Maria Reading*</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>

</div>

<p>Kate Marhelko is a graduate from the Fashion Institute of Technology with a BFA in Textile and Surface Design and obtained a Masters in Early Childhood Education from Bloomsburg University of Pennsylvania. Kate has designed consumer products for Disney, The MLB and the hand warmers the NFL players wear during her time living in Manhattan. She also was a top 5 finalist to Miss Pennsylvania International, Miss Pennsylvania Intercontinental, held the title of Miss Pennsylvania American Coed with the MAC system, Miss Greater Hazleton and Miss Hershey Area a preliminary to the Miss America Organization. Kate is currently an active volunteer with the Miss Greater Hazleton Scholarship Organization, an affiliate with the Miss Pennsylvania Volunteer Inc, where she has actively mentoring current title holders and assisting preparation for the state pageant. Currently Kate is known for her most favorite title of all, “Miss. Marhelko” as she is an elementary art teacher in the Hazleton Area School District.</p>

<p class="mb-5">Through all of Kate’s accomplishments, she just found out later in life that she has Attention Deficit Hyperactive Disorder, otherwise known as ADHD. Kate will be addressing the SNAP program regarding her disability from a personal and professional level as an educator. She will discuss the challenges she faces herself and how she has been able to reach so many students with neurodivergent and intellectual disabilities since her diagnosis. Kate is currently working on becoming a self published author and illustrator. She hopes her children’s book, Arnie Discovers He’s Different, brings representation into the classroom and educates our youth on truly what ADHD is. Kate hopes to inspire the students of PITT and bring light to neurodivergent community with this opportunity.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Kate Marhelko joins SNAP@Pitt to talk about ADHD]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SNAP Club GBM #3 + Speaker Meeting</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/02/GBM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SNAP Club GBM #3 + Speaker Meeting" /><published>2022-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-11-02T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/02/GBM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/11/02/GBM"><![CDATA[<h1 id="event-recording">Event Recording</h1>
<p><strong>You may need to login in to your Pitt University Computing Account, if prompted</strong></p>
<iframe src="https://pitt.hosted.panopto.com/Panopto/Pages/Embed.aspx?id=a808c273-5d41-4a07-a351-af41016c1999&amp;autoplay=false&amp;offerviewer=true&amp;showtitle=true&amp;showbrand=true&amp;captions=false&amp;interactivity=all" height="600" width="100%" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay"></iframe>

<h1 id="slides-from-the-gbm">Slides from the GBM</h1>
<iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vSsGsnKGVF-rwmKczjumK-qQaTFRBOyc6iDCnBh5A2io66GXe2KnRSvK__p5ov37inpNzL-z3ZWaVhT/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=300000" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="715" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true"></iframe>

<h2 id="speaker-article-double-empathy-why-autistic-people-are-often-misunderstood1"><a href="/assets/frym-09-554875.pdf">Speaker Article: Double Empathy: Why Autistic People Are Often Misunderstood</a><sup>1</sup></h2>

<p><sup>1</sup> (https://kids.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/frym.2021.554875)[https://kids.frontiersin.org/articles/10.3389/frym.2021.554875]</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SNAP Club" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Updates on SNAP Volunteering, Nature Walk, Committee, and more]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Oh SNAP! October Edition</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/25/newsletter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Oh SNAP! October Edition" /><published>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/25/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/25/newsletter"><![CDATA[<p>Throughout the month of October, SNAP was able to maintain productivity and expand upon the group’s foundational activities at the University of Pittsburgh. Another general body meeting, speaker meeting, and community event were all held as SNAP gears towards becoming more and more involved and effective. Our general body meeting focused upon discussion of what is next for our aspiring organization; for instance, our events committee, pictured below, was detailed and began functioning in full force! This group of SNAP members is dedicated to planning out community activities, such as our nature walk. With regards to our nature walk, the SNAP members were able to enjoy a lovely morning walk in Schenley Park; the goal of meeting the other members and becoming a more closely-knit club was evidently achieved on behalf of the participants.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">![Events Committee](/assets/Events_Cmte.jpg){: .w-50}</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">**SNAP Club Events Committee**</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Our speaker meeting, as aforementioned, featured Dr. Anto Bagić, who fostered an intriguing presentation based upon critical neurological concepts and the topic of
epilepsy. Dr. Bagić’s research with MEG was also discussed throughout the course of the conversation. We thank Dr. Bagić for joining us, as well as for inspiring our
members to continue striving to help those who are neurodiverse! Up next for SNAP is a third general board meeting, which will be held on the second of November. We look forward to discussing volunteering ventures, future agenda, and more time for group bonding.</p>

<table>
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">![Anto Bagić](https://www.neurology.pitt.edu/sites/default/files/person-images/Bagic-Anto.jpg){: .w-25}</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">**Anto Bagić, MD, PhD, FAES, FACNS**</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p>Last but not least, SNAP is extraordinarily excited to announce that our organization will be involved in a mural project, captained by artist Alison Zapata,
which will creatively represent the neurodiverse community. More details regarding this program will be announced in the very near future on SNAP’s social
media accounts. If you have not yet, make sure to follow SNAP on Instagram <a href="https://www.instagram.com/snapatpitt/">@snapatpitt</a>!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Welcoming the SNAP Events Committee; Dr. Anto Bagić; and a SNAP Mural?]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SNAP Club GBM #2</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/05/GBM" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SNAP Club GBM #2" /><published>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/05/GBM</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/05/GBM"><![CDATA[<h1 id="gbm-recording">GBM Recording</h1>
<iframe src="https://pitt.hosted.panopto.com/Panopto/Pages/Embed.aspx?id=2bacdf2a-ac75-463e-a6a8-af25016094b4&amp;autoplay=false&amp;offerviewer=true&amp;showtitle=true&amp;showbrand=true&amp;captions=false&amp;interactivity=all" height="600" width="100%" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen="" allow="autoplay"></iframe>

<h1 id="slides-from-the-gbm">Slides from the GBM</h1>
<iframe src="https://docs.google.com/presentation/d/e/2PACX-1vTt0w9WaDYPzLkbIYqmCd6LE3auJ_L1mr6wMVYtsaT_n2317pb6ZlFd6IOBo9JSzsI3Z4eKcqUX2w3t/embed?start=false&amp;loop=false&amp;delayms=60000" frameborder="0" width="100%" height="715" allowfullscreen="true" mozallowfullscreen="true" webkitallowfullscreen="true"></iframe>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="SNAP Club" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Updates on SNAP Volunteering, Nature Walk, Committee, and more]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Evening with Anto Bagić</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/03/speaker-event" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Evening with Anto Bagić" /><published>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-10-03T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/03/speaker-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/10/03/speaker-event"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong>: 10/19/2022<br />
<strong>Time</strong>: 5:00 PM - 6:00 PM<br />
<strong>Location</strong>: Zoom (RSVP for Link)</p>

<p>Join SNAP for “<em>An Evening with Anto Bagić</em>” on Wednesday, October 19th at 5:00 pm via Zoom! The event will last one hour and include a moderated Q&amp;A. Tickets are not required for the event, but attendees must complete the RSVP form.</p>

<p>Participants with disabilities are encouraged to contact the SNAP Officers by E-mail at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">snapfse@gmail.com</code> for proper accommodations.</p>

<p class="text-center"><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScRZ-tPZapvOPr-qcEKG1omviF7-qxVlSpvZo-aThHpeJKrPQ/viewform" class="btn disabled btn-primary">RSVP Here</a></p>
<h2 id="about-anto-bagić">About Anto Bagić</h2>
<div class="w-25 float-end me-2 mb-2" style="max-width: 150px">
  <table>
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th style="text-align: center">![Anto Bagić](https://www.neurology.pitt.edu/sites/default/files/person-images/Bagic-Anto.jpg){: .w-100 .img-thumbnail .d-block .img-fluid}</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">**Anto Bagić, MD, PhD, FAES, FACNS**</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>

</div>

<p>Dr. <a href="https://www.neurology.pitt.edu/people/anto-bagic-md-phd-faes-facns"><strong>Anto Bagić</strong></a> (MD, PhD, FAES, FACNS) is an expert in Neurology focusing on the effects of epilepsy and different care techniques such as MEG (magnetoencephalography). He currently is working alongside UPMC in developing an Epilepsy System of Care. He continues to explore the world of epilepsy and expand the world of research and knowledge within the field.</p>

<p>His current positions include:</p>
<ul>
  <li>Professor, University of Pittsburgh’s School of Medicine</li>
  <li>Chief, Epilepsy Division</li>
  <li>Director, UPMC Epilepsy Monitoring Unit (EMU)</li>
  <li>Director, University of Pittsburgh Comprehensive Epilepsy Center (UPCEC)</li>
  <li>Director, UPMC MEG Epilepsy Program</li>
  <li>Chief Scientific Advisor, MEG Research</li>
  <li>Adjunct Professor, Department of Biomedical Engineering, Carnegie Mellon University (CMU)</li>
</ul>

<p><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Anto Bagić joins SNAP@Pitt to talk about causes and effects of epilepsy and how we all can help those with epilepsy]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">An Evening with Maria Reading</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/23/speaker-event" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="An Evening with Maria Reading" /><published>2022-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/23/speaker-event</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/23/speaker-event"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Date</strong>: 09/28/2022<br />
<strong>Time</strong>: 5:30 PM - 6:00 PM<br />
<strong>Location</strong>: Zoom (RSVP for Link)</p>

<p>Join SNAP for “<em>An Evening with Maria Reading</em>” on Wednesday, September 28th at 5:30 pm via Zoom! The event will last one hour and include a moderated Q&amp;A. Tickets are not required for the event, but attendees must complete the RSVP form.</p>

<p>Participants with disabilities are encouraged to contact the SNAP Officers by E-mail at <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">snapfse@gmail.com</code> for proper accommodations.</p>

<p class="text-center"><a href="https://docs.google.com/forms/d/e/1FAIpQLScRZ-tPZapvOPr-qcEKG1omviF7-qxVlSpvZo-aThHpeJKrPQ/viewform" class="btn btn-primary">RSVP Here</a></p>
<h2 id="about-maria-reading">About Maria Reading</h2>

<div class="w-25 float-start me-2 mb-2" style="max-width: 150px">
  <table>
    <thead>
      <tr>
        <th style="text-align: center">![Maria Reading](/assets/maria-reading.png){: .w-100 .img-thumbnail .d-block .img-fluid}</th>
      </tr>
    </thead>
    <tbody>
      <tr>
        <td style="text-align: center">*Maria Reading*</td>
      </tr>
    </tbody>
  </table>

</div>

<p class="mb-5">Maria Reading, M.S. CCC-SLP is a Speech-Language Pathologist currently employed in a school based setting. She received a Bachelor of Science degree in Communication Sciences and Disorders from The Pennsylvania State University in 2014, and a Master of Science Degree in Speech-Language Pathology from East Stroudsburg University of Pennsylvania in 2016.  She has completed clinical work in early intervention, private clinic services, inpatient rehabilitation, and acute hospital care in addition to her school based experience. She strives to help her students achieve functional communication, allowing them complete and full access to their academic curriculum.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<p><br /></p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Maria Reading joins SNAP@Pitt to talk about ADHD]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">SNAP Jumping Into Fall!</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/19/newsletter" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SNAP Jumping Into Fall!" /><published>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-09-19T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/19/newsletter</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/blog/2022/09/19/newsletter"><![CDATA[<p>The month of September was an exciting one for SNAP’s University of Pittsburgh based organization, as several meetings were held in order to introduce the program’s objectives and functionality to potential new members. In addition, volunteering connections were officially established between SNAP and UPMC; following the conduction of required training, the volunteering will begin and further serve as a means of giving our club members a chance to directly assist with helping neurodiverse individuals. Our first general body meeting was a success, as we had north of a collective twenty students join us in-person and virtually. Members were debriefed about the club’s standard requirements, as well as options to become more involved. One such option is the subsidiary events board, which accompanies the primary board in establishing plans for future ‘specialty’ events (more on this later!). Our goal is to have this board filled with dedicated members throughout the course of the current semester.</p>

<h2 id="sparks-in-snap-volunteering">Sparks in SNAP Volunteering</h2>

<table class="w-25 float-end me-2 mb-0">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">![Zachary Miller, Working at UPMC](/assets/working-at-upmc.jpeg){: .w-100 .img-thumbnail .d-block .img-fluid}</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">*Working at UPMC*</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">(pictured Zachary Miller)</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>At UPMC, via the program which <strong>SNAP club extends to involved members</strong>, the volunteers will gain first-hand experience with aiding people with special needs. We hope that this will benefit everyone involved, as meaningful connections and experience are expected to be fostered. SNAP volunteers will be working with anyone that defines themselves as being disabled (under the age of 75). Social, emotional, and physical support, in particular, will be provided to patients. Concrete needs, via the work of volunteers, such as fidget toys, stuffed animals, and coloring books, will also be provided to patients. More updates will be provided on future newsletters, as volunteering begins and is hopefully taken up on!</p>

<h2 id="first-snap-event">First SNAP Event</h2>
<p>Upcoming events of the club also include a <strong>Nature Walk</strong>, which is being planned for late September/early October. We will be partnering with a local neurodiverse organization in order to make this event a reality. We very much hope to have an enjoyable and well-weathered experience! Currently, we intend for the walk to take place in Oakland’s Schenley Park.</p>

<h2 id="welcoming-guest-speakers">Welcoming Guest Speakers</h2>

<table class="w-25 float-start me-2 mb-2">
  <thead>
    <tr>
      <th style="text-align: center">![Anto Bagić](https://www.neurology.pitt.edu/sites/default/files/person-images/Bagic-Anto.jpg){: .w-100 .img-thumbnail .d-block .img-fluid}</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td style="text-align: center">**Anto Bagić, MD, PhD, FAES, FACNS**</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Our club further looks forward to welcoming guest speaker <a href="https://www.neurology.pitt.edu/people/anto-bagic-md-phd-faes-facns"><strong>Anto Bagić</strong></a> (MD, PhD, FAES, FACNS) on October 19th to discuss topics pertaining to our organization’s mission and importance.</p>

<p>Dr. Bagić is an expert in Neurology focusing on the effects of epilepsy and different care techniques such as MEG (magnetoencephalography). He currently is working alongside UPMC in developing an Epilepsy System of Care. He continues to explore the world of epilepsy and expand the world of research and knowledge within the field. He is excited to speak with the SNAP community  in the coming month about the causes and effects of epilepsy and how we all can help those with epilepsy.</p>

<p><br /></p>

<h2 id="snap-partners-with-the-reaact-lab-for-asd-research">SNAP Partners with the Reaact Lab for ASD Research</h2>
<p>With regards to SNAP’s research component, we are enthusiastic to announce our <strong>partnership with the Reaact Lab</strong>! We will be starting our first research project in the very near future. This project will involve the surveying of the ASD community. Our second research project is in the initial stages of recruitment, as we await official IRB approval. Additional information regarding each of these projects will be revealed in the coming weeks.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more information regarding the University of Pittsburgh’s SNAP club in the next newsletter!</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="Newsletter" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[SNAP discusses their first event of the semester, developments in SNAP research, and updates with SNAP volunteering!]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We’re looking for a Mobile Software (App) Developer</title><link href="https://snapfse.com/recruiting/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We’re looking for a Mobile Software (App) Developer" /><published>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2022-08-28T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://snapfse.com/recruiting-swe</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://snapfse.com/recruiting/"><![CDATA[<p class="text-center my-0"><a href="/recruiting/apply/" class="btn btn-primary">Apply</a></p>

<h2 id="the-big-picture">The Big Picture</h2>

<p>Can you bring your creative and visionary skills to help make change in the world? You will have the autonomy, access, and support to do meaningful work that has huge impact on the neurodiverse and neurotypical population. Contagious enthusiasm for SNAPFSE’s mission and the passion to learn is essential in this role.</p>

<h2 id="about-us">About Us</h2>

<p><a href="http://snapfse.com">Special Needs Assistance Program for Social Engagement</a> (<strong>SNAPFSE</strong>) was created to increase the engagement, awareness, and communication between neurodiverse and neurotypical people, bringing both groups together to create a stronger bond and better understanding of each other. SNAP expands into four individual projects, each with its unique mission to spread love and support for neurodiversity.</p>

<p class="text-center my-0"><a href="https://snapfse.com/story/" class="btn btn-primary">Read More</a></p>

<h2 id="responsibilities-include">Responsibilities Include</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Producing efficient and maintainable code based on defined requirements.</li>
  <li>Testing and deploying programs and applications.</li>
  <li>Troubleshooting, debugging, maintaining, and improving existing software.</li>
  <li>Reviewing and assessing user feedback to improve software performance and features.</li>
  <li>Collaborate with product team to develop and maintain mobile applications.</li>
  <li>Discuss technical issues with peers and non-technical team members.</li>
  <li>Manage individual project priorities and deadlines.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="project-description">Project Description</h2>

<p>The SNAP App offers a new social media platform for neurodiverse friends to meet, interact, and discover one another. The app will feature:</p>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Ability to schedule and make in-person hangout sessions</strong>: participants can find common meeting spaces suggested by the program to hangout out and meet with new neurodiverse and neurotypical individuals.</li>
  <li><strong>A matching system based on preferences</strong>: Using location, preferences, and tags, SNAP will match you in your feed with like-minded people.</li>
  <li><strong>A chat system with integrated machine learning for easier neurodiverse communication and interpretation</strong>: a chat system will be integrated into the system for easy, quick communication with new people that you meet. It will also include special needs capabilities that allow for neurodiverse participants to have more ease and comfort with communication.</li>
  <li><strong>The SNAP Research Initiative (SRI)</strong>: SRI is a research component linked to a larger project. The SRI will give consenting individuals the opportunity to contribute to ASD research by prompting participants to fill out a questionnaire after social interactions.</li>
  <li><strong>A “support” (aid) account linking system</strong>: Supports can join SNAP and help their participant in the program</li>
  <li><strong>Video chat feature for virtual meets</strong>: a video call system will be available for virtual hangouts for those that prefer to not meet in-person or may have difficulty otherwise meeting outside.</li>
</ol>

<h2 id="skills-and-experience">Skills And Experience</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Ability to work independently.</li>
  <li>Bachelor’s degree not required.</li>
  <li>Mobile app development experience required.</li>
  <li>Developing and maintaining new and existing code for mobile applications following best practices using the <strong>React Native framework.</strong></li>
  <li>Experience working with RESTful APIs.</li>
  <li>Experience working with cloud systems such as <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">AWS</code> or <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Firebase</code>.</li>
  <li>Understanding of source control, specifically <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">git</code>.</li>
  <li>Interest and ability to learn other programming languages as needed.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="nice-to-have">Nice to have</h2>

<ul>
  <li>Analytical thinker with exceptional problem-solving skills.</li>
  <li>Experience with <code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">Tailwind CSS</code>.</li>
  <li>Understanding of engineering and design best practices, such as: design patterns, testable code, mobile performance, responsive design, and accessibility.</li>
  <li>Understanding of the agile process.</li>
</ul>

<h2 id="diversity-equity-and-inclusion">Diversity, Equity, and Inclusion</h2>

<p>We believe diversity breeds innovation. We are actively looking to add members to our team who will bring diverse backgrounds, new perspectives, and a willingness to challenge us to improve the work we do every day.</p>

<p class="text-center"><a href="/recruiting/apply/" class="btn btn-primary">Apply</a></p>

<p>Contact <a href="mailto:shinwookim@pitt.edu"><code class="language-plaintext highlighter-rouge">shinwookim@pitt.edu</code></a> if you have any questions or concerns.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="News" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Join us in bringing the neurodiverse and the neurotypical communities together]]></summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" /><media:content medium="image" url="https://snapfse.com/assets/snap_team.jpg" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>